<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home</title>
    <link>https://alisherm.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2023–2024, Alisher Muzaffarov and the alisherm.dev; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 09:44:20 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alisherm.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A simple go, gin, and sqlc combination walkthrough</title>
      <link>https://alisherm.dev/posts/go-gin-sqlc-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 09:44:20 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alisherm.dev/posts/go-gin-sqlc-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>Well, in this post we will see a partial implementation of a medium.com-like app called Conduit. Take a brief look at the backend implementation specs. As you can see, there are APIs for users, articles, tags, and so on. For now, we will implement user registration and login endpoints; api/users and api/users/login. In the end, we will be able to execute the two curl requests successfully:&#xA;# 1. user registration request curl --location &amp;#39;http://localhost:8085/api/users&amp;#39; \ --header &amp;#39;Content-Type: application/json&amp;#39; \ --data-raw &amp;#39;{ &amp;#34;user&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;username&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;johndoe&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;email&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;johndoe@example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to OCPP(Open Charge Point Protocol)</title>
      <link>https://alisherm.dev/posts/introduction-to-ocpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 15:30:18 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alisherm.dev/posts/introduction-to-ocpp/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, electical vehicles have become more and more popular. As a result, the number of charging stations has increased significantly. There is no doubt that this new trend comes with its own challenges. For instance, managing multiple charging stations remotely, monitoring them in real-time, providing a seamless user experience, etc. Of course, those challenges can be addressed by creating backend systems that can communicate with charging stations. Again we have interoperability issues between charging stations and backend systems of different manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://alisherm.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 09:30:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alisherm.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Greetings! I&amp;rsquo;m a backend engineer specializing in Golang, with over 2.5 years of experience in building backend API services using Golang and Python. I also have some experience in DevOps. Passionate about exploring new technologies, I thrive in both team settings and solo projects, always aiming to excel in my field. Take a look at my resume to learn more about my experience and skills!&#xA;Languages Golang, SQL, Python, Javascript.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://alisherm.dev/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alisherm.dev/search/</guid>
      <description>search</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
