<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alisher Muzaffarov</title><link>https://alisherm.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Alisher Muzaffarov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 15:30:18 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alisherm.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://alisherm.dev/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 09:30:59 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://alisherm.dev/about/</guid><description>I am a backend engineer with extensive experience in building and managing cloud-native applications. My expertise in devops, particularly with Kubernetes, has given me a unique perspective on how to build and manage large-scale, production-grade applications. Download my resume.
Languages golang, python, NoSQL, SQL, javascript, HTML and CSS.
Services Docker, Kubernetes, AWS (learning), NATS, Prometheus, Grafana, Linkerd, Github, Gitea, Mattermost.
Frameworks Echo, Gorilla/Websocket, Sanic, FastAPI and Bootstrap.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to OCPP(Open Charge Point Protocol)</title><link>https://alisherm.dev/posts/ocpp-deep-dive-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 15:30:18 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://alisherm.dev/posts/ocpp-deep-dive-1/</guid><description>In recent years, electical vehicles have become more and more popular. As a result, the number of charging stations has increased significantly. There is no doubt that this new trend comes with its own challenges. For instance, managing multiple charging stations remotely, monitoring them in real-time, providing a seamless user experience, etc. Of course, those challenges can be addressed by creating backend systems that can communicate with charging stations. Again we have interoperability issues between charging stations and backend systems of different manufacturers.</description></item></channel></rss>